<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="30">
	<TITLE>Askja</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<SENTENCE ID="1.1">
			<REFERENCE ID="1" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Askja</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> is a stratovolcano situated in a remote part of the central highlands of Iceland (location: 65.03° N, 16.75° W).</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="1.2">
			<STRING>The name Askja refers to a complex of nested calderas within the surrounding Dyngjufjöll mountains, which rise to 1,510m. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<SENTENCE ID="2.1">
			<STRING>The region is only accessible for a few months of the year.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.2">
			<STRING>Being situated in the rain-shadow to the NE of the Vatnajökull icecap, the area receives only about 450 mm of rainfall annually.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.3">
			<STRING>The area was used during training for the Apollo program to prepare astronauts for potential lunar conditions. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="3">
		<SENTENCE ID="3.1">
			<REFERENCE ID="2" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Askja</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> was virtually unknown until the tremendous eruption which started on March 29, 1875.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="3.2">
			<STRING>Especially in the eastern fjords of Iceland, the ashfall was heavy enough to poison the land and kill livestock.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="3.3">
			<STRING>The eruption triggered a substantial wave of emigration from Iceland.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="3.4">
			<STRING>The last eruption of  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="3" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">the Askja</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> was in 1961. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="4">
		<SENTENCE ID="4.1">
			<STRING>The outer caldera of  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="4" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Askja</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING>, representing a prehistoric eruption, is about 45 km², and there is evidence of other later caldera-forming events within it.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="4.2">
			<STRING>The main crater floor lies at about 1,100m. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="5">
		<SENTENCE ID="5.1">
			<STRING>Öskjuvatn is a large lake that fills much of the smaller caldera resulting from the 1875 eruption.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="5.2">
			<STRING>Its surface lies about 50m below the level of the main crater floor and covers about 12km².</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="5.3">
			<STRING>When the lake originally formed it was warm, but today it is frozen over for most of the year.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="5.4">
			<STRING>Öskjuvatn is the deepest lake in Iceland at 220 m deep. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="6">
		<SENTENCE ID="6.1">
			<STRING>Viti is a smaller explosion crater on the north east shore of Öskjuvatn, approximately 100 metres diameter.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="6.2">
			<STRING>It contains a geothermal lake of mineral-rich, sulphurous, opaque blue water, which is maintained at a comfortable temperature for swimming.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="6.3">
			<STRING>Víti was formed in the eruption of 1875. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="7">
		<SENTENCE ID="7.1">
			<STRING>In 1907, the German scientists Walter von Knebel and Max Rudloff visited  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="5" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Askja</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> to study the caldera.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="7.2">
			<STRING>While exploring Öskjuvatn in a small boat, they disappeared without a trace.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="7.3">
			<STRING>Von Knebel's fiancée Ina von Grumbkow led an expedition to search for them, but no indication of what happened to them was ever found. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="8">
		<SENTENCE ID="8.1">
			<STRING>In the Dyngjufjöll mountains which surround the Askja caldera can be found the impressive Drekagil, the canyon of dragons.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="8.2">
			<STRING>Not far from  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="6" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Askja</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING>, there are two other interesting volcanic systems: Herðubreið and Kverkfjöll. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="9">
		<SENTENCE ID="9.1">
			<REFERENCE ID="7" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Askja</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> is a popular tourist destination.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="9.2">
			<STRING>There are two mountain huts and a campsite at Dreki, by Drekagil, which is about 100km by unpaved road from the Icelandic ring-road.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="9.3">
			<STRING>A dirt road climbs 8km up from Dreki into the Askja caldera.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="9.4">
			<STRING>It is a walk of about 2.5km from the car park to Öskjuvatn and Víti.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="9.5">
			<STRING>The roads are usually only open for about two or three months in high summer. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
