<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="43">
	<TITLE>Bidean nam Bian</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<SENTENCE ID="1.1">
			<REFERENCE ID="1" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Bidean nam Bian</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING>, lying to the south of Glen Coe, Highland, Scotland, is the highest point in the historic county of Argyllshire.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="1.2">
			<REFERENCE ID="2" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="nominative" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="pronoun" TYPE="pronoun">It</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> is a complex mountain, with many ridges and subsidiary peaks, one of which, Stob Coire Sgreamhach, is classified as a separate Munro. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<SENTENCE ID="2.1">
			<STRING>The most noticeable features of  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="3" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Bidean nam Bian</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> are the famous Three Sisters of Glen Coe, three peaks (in reality simply the steep ends of ridges) that face north into the Glen.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.2">
			<STRING>Two of the sisters, Gearr Aonach (Short Ridge) and Aonach Dubh (Black Ridge) converge at Stob Coire nan Lochan, a 1,115 m subsidiary peak of  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="4" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Bidean nam Bian</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> that lies about 1 km to the northeast of the actual summit.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.3">
			<STRING>The final, most easterly sister, Beinn Fhada, joins the Bidean nam Bian massif at the summit of Stob Coire Sgreamhach. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="3">
		<SENTENCE ID="3.1">
			<STRING>Beinn Fhada is separated from Gearr Aonach by a glen known as Coire Gabhail.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="3.2">
			<STRING>This translates to Glen of Capture, however the glen is more normally known as the Hidden or Lost Valley.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="3.3">
			<STRING>Either name may be considered appropriate since it is believed that in former times the valley was used by members of Clan Macdonald to hide stolen cattle.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="3.4">
			<STRING>The glen is ideal for this purpose since it is blocked by a glacial landslip, and from Glen Coe appears as a narrow gorge.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="3.5">
			<STRING>In fact, once past the landslip the floor of the glen is wide and flat – ideal for cattle.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="3.6">
			<STRING>The path from Glen Coe through the gorge into Coire Gabhail is a popular short walk (around 4 km in total), though it is rough in places. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
