<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="1028">
	<TITLE>Brussels</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<SENTENCE ID="1.1">
			<REFERENCE ID="1" SEMCAT="city" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Brussels</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> ([French: Bruxelles], pronounced [IPA: [bʁysɛl]], and sometimes [IPA: [bʁyksɛl]] by non-Belgian speakers of French; [Tutch: Brussel], pronounced [IPA: [brʁsəl]]; [German: Brüssel]) is the capital of Belgium, the French Community of Belgium, the Flemish Community and the main seat of the European Union's institutions (and thus often considered 'The Capital of Europe'). </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<SENTENCE ID="2.1">
			<REFERENCE ID="2" SEMCAT="city" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Brussels</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> is, first of all, a city located in the centre of Belgium and  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="3" SEMCAT="city" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="" EMPHATIC="" HEAD="" TYPE="empty">_</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> is its capital, but it sometimes also refers to the largest municipality of the Brussels-Capital Region.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.2">
			<STRING>This municipality inside  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="4" SEMCAT="city" SYNCAT="np-obj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Brussels</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> is correctly named The City of Brussels (French: Bruxelles-Ville or Ville de Bruxelles, Dutch: Stad Brussel), which is one of 19 municipalities that make up the Brussels-Capital Region (see also: Municipalities of the Brussels-Capital Region).</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.3">
			<STRING>The municipality has a population of about 140,000 while the Brussels-Capital Region has 1,018,804 inhabitants (1 January 2006).</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.4">
			<STRING>The Metropolitan area has about 2,090,000 inhabitants. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="3">
		<SENTENCE ID="3.1">
			<STRING>The Brussels-Capital Region is a region of Belgium in its own right (Région à part entière), alongside Wallonia and the Flemish Region.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="3.2">
			<STRING>Geographically and linguistically, it is a (bilingual) enclave in the (unilingual) Flemish Region.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="3.3">
			<STRING>Regions are one component of Belgium's complex institutions, the three communities being &quot;the&quot; other component: the Brussels inhabitants must deal with either the French (speaking) community or the Flemish Community for matters such as culture and education. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="4">
		<SENTENCE ID="4.1">
			<REFERENCE ID="5" SEMCAT="city" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Brussels</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> is also the capital of both the French Community of Belgium (Communauté française Wallonie-Bruxelles in French) and of Flanders (Vlaanderen); all Flemish capital institutions are established here: Flemish Parliament, Flemish government and its administration (though Antwerp is considered the cultural capital of Flanders). </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="5">
		<SENTENCE ID="5.1">
			<STRING>Two of the main institutions of the European Union - the European Commission and the Council of the European Union - have their headquarters in  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="6" SEMCAT="city" SYNCAT="np-obj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Brussels</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING>: the Commission in the Berlaymont building and the Council in the Justus Lipsius building facing it.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="5.2">
			<STRING>The third institution, the European Parliament, also has a parliamentary chamber in  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="7" SEMCAT="city" SYNCAT="np-obj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Brussels</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> in which its committee meet and some of its plenary sessions are held (the other plenary sessions are held in Strasbourg, and its administrative headquarters are in Luxembourg). </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="6">
		<SENTENCE ID="6.1">
			<REFERENCE ID="8" SEMCAT="city" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Brussels</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> is also the political seat of NATO, the North Atlantic Treaty Organisation, the Western European Union (WEU) and EUROCONTROL, the European Organisation for the Safety of Air Navigation </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="7">
		<SENTENCE ID="7.1">
			<STRING>Due to this, some countries have three ambassadors present in  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="9" SEMCAT="city" SYNCAT="np-obj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Brussels</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING>: the normal bi-lateral ambassador, the EU-ambassador, and finally the NATO-ambassador. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="8">
		<SENTENCE ID="8.1">
			<STRING>The &quot;language border&quot; divides Belgium into a northern, Dutch-speaking region, and a southern, French-speaking region.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="8.2">
			<STRING>Although the real language border and the official one are largely identical, there are bilingual pockets on both sides with, in certain cases, no specific linguistic rights for the population speaking the other language.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="8.3">
			<STRING>The Brussels-Capital Region is officially bilingual, while the majority of its residents speak French (see the linguistic history of  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="10" SEMCAT="city" SYNCAT="np-obj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Brussels</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> in this article: linguistic situation section). </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="9">
		<SENTENCE ID="9.1">
			<STRING>The highest building in  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="11" SEMCAT="city" SYNCAT="np-obj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Brussels</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> is the South Tower (150 m); the most famous probably the Atomium, which is a remnant from the 1958 World Exposition. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
