<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="151">
	<TITLE>Elliott Knob</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<SENTENCE ID="1.1">
			<REFERENCE ID="1" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Elliott Knob</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> is one of the highest mountains in the northern portions of the U.S. state of Virginia.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="1.2">
			<STRING>At 4,463 feet (1,360 m),  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="2" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">the peak</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> is located on the northern point of the ridge known as Great North Mountain.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="1.3">
			<STRING>A small, naturally growing stand of spruce trees are on the summit, indicating that the altitude is just high enough to support tree species normally found hundreds of miles to the north.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="1.4">
			<STRING>Otherwise oak and hickory trees are the most common types found on  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="3" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">the mountain</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING>.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="1.5">
			<REFERENCE ID="4" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">The mountain</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> is entirely within George Washington and Jefferson National Forests. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<SENTENCE ID="2.1">
			<STRING>The area around  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="5" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">the mountain</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> is inhabited by a wide array of fauna including Black Bears, White-tailed Deer and the elusive Bobcat. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="3">
		<SENTENCE ID="3.1">
			<STRING>There is a Forest Service lookout tower, which is closed to the public, on top of  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="6" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">the mountain</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING>.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="3.2">
			<STRING>A primitive jeep trail ascends  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="7" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">the mountain</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> from the east but it is also closed to public vehicles.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="3.3">
			<STRING>The jeep trail is used by the USFS to gain access to a fire lookout on the summit, and rises over 2,000 feet (610 m) in less than 4 miles (6.4 km).</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="3.4">
			<STRING>The only access for the public is on foot and along with the jeep trail, several other trails can be used to ascend to the top, each averaging 5 miles (8 km) in length and climbing up to 2,300 feet (700 m) from the trailheads.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="3.5">
			<STRING>A small grassy cove is on the top and there is a spring 200 yards (200 m) below the summit which flows year round as well as a small man made pond not far from the spring. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="4">
		<SENTENCE ID="4.1">
			<STRING>Right beside the base of the fire tower there is a National Geodetic Survey triangulation station disk.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="4.2">
			<STRING>The entire firetower structure is enclosed within a fence with barbed wire at the top.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="4.3">
			<STRING>However there is evidence of people gaining entry in the form of holes under the fence and loose sections where the fence can be pulled up high enough for a person to crawl under, since the ground is only covered with grass in that area of the summit. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
