<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="213">
	<TITLE>Hkakabo Razi</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<SENTENCE ID="1.1">
			<REFERENCE ID="1" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Hkakabo Razi</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> (Burmese: ) is Southeast Asia's highest mountain, located in the northern Burma state of Kachin.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="1.2">
			<REFERENCE ID="2" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">The peak</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> is enclosed within Hkakabo Razi National Park.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="1.3">
			<REFERENCE ID="3" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="nominative" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="pronoun" TYPE="pronoun">It</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> is entirely mountainous and  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="4" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="" EMPHATIC="" HEAD="" TYPE="empty">_</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> is characterized by broad-leaved evergreen rain forest, a sub-tropical temperate zone from 8,000 ft. --9,000 ft. (2,438 m to 2,743 m), then broad-leaved, semi-deciduous forest and finally needle-leaved evergreen, snow forest.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="1.4">
			<STRING>Above 11,000 ft. (3,353 m) the highest forest zone is alpine, different not only in kind from the forest, but different in history and origin.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="1.5">
			<STRING>Still higher up, around 15,000 ft. (4,572 m), cold, barren, windswept terrain and permanent snow and glaciers dominate.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="1.6">
			<STRING>At around 17,500 ft. (5,334 m), there is a large ice cap with several outlet glaciers. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<SENTENCE ID="2.1">
			<REFERENCE ID="5" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Hkakabo Razi</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> was established as a natural reserve on January 30, 1996 and as a National Park on November 10, 1998.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.2">
			<STRING>The park is the last stronghold for biodiversity in Burma.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.3">
			<STRING>Extraordinarily rich flora and fauna, ranging from lowland tropical to alpine species still await proper research and identification.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.4">
			<STRING>They have barely been studied, and the park remains an excellent center for field study for students of botany, geology, zoology and geography.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.5">
			<STRING>A study was done by the Forest Department with the assistance of Wildlife Conservation Society of New York during 1997 and 1998.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.6">
			<STRING>The results have been presented in ICIMOD sponsored Workshop “Sub-regional Consultation on Conservation of Hkakabo Razi Mountain Ecosystems in Eastern Himalayas”, held in Putao, Burma during October 25--29, 1999.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.7">
			<STRING>This was followed in 2001 with an international, interdisciplinary team of scientists from the California Academy of Sciences in San Francisco, National Geographic Society, Harvard University, the Chinese Academy of Sciences, and the Myanmar Forestry Ministry.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.8">
			<STRING>On September 11, 2001, herpetologist Joseph Slowinski, team leader from California Academy of Sciences, was bitten by a venoumous krait and died in the field.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.9">
			<STRING>In 2002-2003, P. Christiaan Klieger, anthropologist from California Academy of Sciences and photographer Dong Lin retraced their previous steps, and succeeded in making the first anthropological survey of the Hkakabo Razi region.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.10">
			<STRING>On foot they reached the northern-most village in Burma, Tehuandan, which is inhabited by about 200 Khampa Tibetans, including mountaineer Nyama Gyaltsen (see below). </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="3">
		<SENTENCE ID="3.1">
			<STRING>The region will shortly be opened to the general public through eco-tourism by the Burma authorities.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="3.2">
			<STRING>The government is collecting information for development in that regard and a number of scientific expeditions have been already accepted in the region. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
