<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="771">
	<TITLE>Mont Maudit</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<SENTENCE ID="1.1">
			<REFERENCE ID="1" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mont Maudit</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> (4,465 m) is a mountain in the Mont Blanc massif in France and Italy.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="1.2">
			<STRING>Until the end of the 18th century, Mont Blanc and its satellite peaks were collectively known in French as the Montagne Maudite. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<SENTENCE ID="2.1">
			<STRING>The first ascent of  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="2" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mont Maudit</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> was by a British party comprising Henry Seymour Hoare and the lawyer/diplomat William Edward Davidson with guides Johann Jaun and Johann von Bergen on 12 September 1878.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.2">
			<STRING>The route they took was via the south ridge, during an ascent of Mont Blanc by the Corridor route. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="3">
		<SENTENCE ID="3.1">
			<STRING>The southern side of  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="3" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">the mountain</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> is considerably steeper than the gentle snow slopes of the northern side and features the well-known south-east or Frontier ridge (also known as the Kuffner ridge, D).</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="3.2">
			<STRING>This route was first climbed by Moritz von Kuffner with guides Alex­ander Burgener and Josef Furrer from 2–4 July 1887.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="3.3">
			<STRING>George Mallory, in a party led by R. L. G. Irving, made the third ascent of the route in 1911.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="3.4">
			<STRING>Ascents of the ridge start from the hut on the Col du Trident and take at least seven to eight hours. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="4">
		<SENTENCE ID="4.1">
			<REFERENCE ID="4" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">The mountain</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> in served by the following huts:* Refuge des Cosmiques (3,613 m, guarded February–October)* Abri Simond Bivouac (beside the Refuge des Cosmiques and open in winter when the Refuge is closed)* Rifugio Torino (3,322 m/3,375 m, 2 huts: a lower and older one and an upper, newer hut, connected by a tunnel)* Bivacco Lucia e Piero Ghiglione (3,690 m, guarded 20 June–20 September, also known as the Trident hut)* Bivacco Alberico e Brogna (3,679 m, also known as the Bivouac de la Fourche) </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
