<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="1381">
	<TITLE>Spratly Islands</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<SENTENCE ID="1.1">
			<REFERENCE ID="1" SEMCAT="country" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">The Spratly Islands</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> are a disputed group of approximately 100 reefs and islets in the South China Sea.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="1.2">
			<STRING>Part of the South China Sea Islands,  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="2" SEMCAT="country" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">the Spratly Islands</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> are surrounded by rich fishing grounds and gas and oil deposits, whose true extent is unknown and disputed.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="1.3">
			<STRING>The People's Republic of China (PRC), the Republic of China (Taiwan), and Vietnam each claim sovereignty over  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="3" SEMCAT="country" SYNCAT="np-obj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">the entire group of islands</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING>, while Brunei, Malaysia, and the Philippines each claim various parts.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="1.4">
			<STRING>Several of the nations involved have soldiers stationed in  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="4" SEMCAT="country" SYNCAT="np-obj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">the Spratlys</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> and control various installations on different islands and reefs.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="1.5">
			<STRING>The Republic of China (Taiwan) occupies one of the largest islands, Taiping (Itu Aba Island).</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="1.6">
			<STRING>In February 1995, the PRC occupied Mischief Reef, creating a political crisis in Southeast Asia, especially with the Philippines.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="1.7">
			<STRING>In early 1999, these disputes escalated as the Philippines claimed that the PRC was building military installations on the reef. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<SENTENCE ID="2.1">
			<STRING>Although the disputes have calmed to some degree, they still remain one of the most plausible scenarios for a major East Asia war involving the PRC or a smaller war between other claimants, a scenario depicted by Tom Clancy in his novel SSN. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
