<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="45">
	<TITLE>Big Hatchet Peak</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<REFERENCE ID="1" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Big Hatchet Peak</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is the high point of the Big Hatchet Mountains, a small but rugged range in the southwest corner (the &quot;Bootheel&quot;) of New Mexico, in the United States. The mountains are located in Hidalgo County, about 50 mi (80 km) southwest of Deming. The range runs roughly northwest-southeast, and is about 12 mi (20 km) long; the southeastern edge of the range is within 5 mi (8 km) of the border with Mexico. They lie primarily on BLM land.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<REFERENCE ID="2" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">The peak</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> rises steeply out of the Playas Valley, to the west, and the Hatchita Valley, to the east of the range. The summit stands about 4,000 feet above the valley floors. Also, the north and west faces of </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="3" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">the peak</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> are particularly steep, making for an impressive mountain. There are a few other minor summits in this small range, but none are named.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="3">
		<STRING>Geologically this range is part of the Basin and Range Province which spans much of the southwestern U.S. and parts of northern Mexico. It is a fault-block range made up of Paleozoic limestone and Cretaceous shale and sandstones.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="4">
		<STRING>The Big Hatchet Mountains are far from population centers, and have no paved road access or developed recreation sites; they therefore see little recreational activity. However the standard route on </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="4" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">the peak</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING>, along the South Ridge from Thompson Canyon, is straightforward.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
