<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="68">
	<TITLE>Cascade Mountain (Alberta)</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<REFERENCE ID="1" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Cascade Mountain</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is a mountain located in the Bow River Valley of Banff National Park, adjacent to the town of Banff. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="2" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">The mountain</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> was named in 1858 by James Hector after the waterfall or cascade on the southern flanks of the peak. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="3" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">The mountain</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> has also been called Stoney Chief, which is related to the name of the smaller neighbouring mountain Stoney Squaw, which is still in use. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="4" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Cascade</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is the highest mountain adjacent to the townsite.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<REFERENCE ID="5" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">The mountain</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> can be climbed starting from the Norquay Ski Area base. The first portion is a fairly moderate hike, up to the Cascade Amphitheatre. Continuing upwards, the route ascends along the ridge edge until it reaches the crest where it dips before it rises to the false summit. While the false summit can be descended at its end, it is much easier to follow a trail around the western side along the exposed foot. Snow typically blocks this route almost until mid July and attempting it while snowy can entail considerable avalanche risk due to the slabby terrain and exposure. A long window of clear weather - full day - should be anticipated before attempting this climb, as many climbers have gotten into trouble and needed rescue (or died) when a storm suddenly blows in.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="3">
		<STRING>Ascent time: 3-4 hoursDescent time: 2-3 hrs</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
