<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="222">
	<TITLE>Humboldt Peak (Colorado)</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<REFERENCE ID="1" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Humboldt Peak</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is a high peak in the Sangre de Cristo Range in southern Colorado. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="2" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="nominative" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="pronoun" TYPE="pronoun">It</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is the least challenging climb of the Crestone group of fourteeners, which include Crestone Peak, Crestone Needle, and Kit Carson Peak. (Challenger Point, a subpeak of Kit Carson Peak, is sometimes included in this list.)</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<STRING>Despite the rather impressive north face of </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="3" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Humboldt Peak</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING>, the standard route on </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="4" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">the peak</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is not much more than a hike along a decent trail with some minor rock scrambling (Class 2) near the summit. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="5" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="nominative" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="pronoun" TYPE="pronoun">It</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is considered an easy climb and </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="6" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="" EMPHATIC="" HEAD="" TYPE="empty">_</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is recommended for those just beginning to climb the fourteeners. The trail climbs </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="7" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">the peak</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> from the South Colony Lakes basin, accessed from the east side of the range. This basin is a popular site that is also the base for most climbs of Crestone Peak and Crestone Needle. A very rugged four-wheel drive road follows the South Colony drainage to near the Lakes; however this road is subject to possible closure in the near future. There is a lower parking lot for two-wheel drive access at the San Isabel National Forest boundary. The climb involves 4,464 feet of elevation gain in a 14 mile round trip when done from the two-wheel drive access point, but only 3,100 feet of gain in a 6 mile round trip from the current high-clearance four-wheel drive access point.As of 8/30/2007, 2WD lot has been moved back. From here climb involves 5,200 feet of elevation gain in an 18 mile round trip.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
