<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="229">
	<TITLE>Illiniza</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<REFERENCE ID="1" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Illiniza</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is a volcano in Ecuador, located about 55 km southwest of Quito. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="2" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Illiniza</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING>, a dormant stratovolcano, consists of two snow covered peaks: Illiniza Sur (5,248 m) and Illiniza Norte (5,126 m). Most guidebooks (for example, Lonely Planet Ecuador, Ecuador: A Climbing Guide) spell the mountain with only one &quot;l&quot; as in Iliniza.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<STRING>Whilst Illiniza Sur is a more difficult climb due to the peak being glacial, Illiniza Norte requires little or no climbing expertise, and may be done as a trekking peak. A guide is still recommended though as the path gets hard to find as the peak is approached.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="3">
		<REFERENCE ID="3" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">The Illinizas</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> are generally thought to be the best acclimatization mountains in Ecuador, and </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="4" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="" EMPHATIC="" HEAD="" TYPE="empty">_</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> are frequently used as a preparatory climb to higher peaks such as Cotopaxi, Chimborazo and Cayambe.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="4">
		<STRING>There is a rustic refuge located between the north and south peaks. It can be reached via a one hour camioneta ride from El Chaupi followed by a three hour climb. The refuge has gas stoves, pots and pans and bunk beds. It is necessary to bring warm sleeping bags and food, but water is available to be boiled.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
