<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="749">
	<TITLE>Kala Patthar</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<REFERENCE ID="1" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Kala Patthar</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is a mountain in the Nepalese Himalaya. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="2" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="nominative" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="pronoun" TYPE="pronoun">It</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> appears as a big brown bump below the impressive south face of Pumori (7,161m / 23,494ft). Many trekkers in the region of Mount Everest will attempt to summit </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="3" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Kala Patthar</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING>, since </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="4" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="nominative" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="pronoun" TYPE="pronoun">it</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> provides the most accessible point to view Mt. Everest from base camp to peak (due to the structure of Everest, the peak cannot be seen from the base camp). The views from almost anywhere on </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="5" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Kala Patthar</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> of Everest, Lhotse and Nuptse are spectacular.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<STRING>The ascent of </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="6" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Kala Patthar</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> begins at Gorakshep (5,164m), the original base camp for Mt. Everest. After a brief dip to an ancient lake bed (which now contains a small lake and a helipad), the ascent makes its way up a series of steep switchbacks before levelling off somewhat as it traverses to the eastern side of </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="7" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">the mountain</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING>. The trail then becomes steep once again until it reaches the wind-swept summit ridge. From there, a five to ten minute scramble over boulders takes one to the top, which is marked with prayer flags. The full ascent usually takes between 1.5 and 2 hours. If the attempt is made starting from Lobuche, an additional two to three hours (one way) is required. Although the elevation is commonly listed as 5,545-5,550m, Portland State University Assistant Professor Dr. Luis A. Ruedas took a Garmin eMap GPS unit to the summit on 6 December 2006. These units have the capability to average a series of individual satellite readings, making them more accurate than single reading machines. Averaging 48 readings at 0625h Nepal local time, temperature -20ยบC, the GPS recorded the location of the summit as 27ยบ59.750'N, 86ยบ49.705'E (datum: WGS84), and elevation as 5,643m. Even accounting for the fact that the summit may have approximately one meter of stones added as a celebratory cairn, this is a significant discrepancy with previously recorded elevations. The same unit was consistent with respect to previously recorded elevations for Gorak Shep and Everest Base Camp. It is possible that since </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="8" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Kala Patthar</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is merely a minor summit on a ridge leading to Pumo Ri, different people may have measured different summits. The summit traditionally referred to as Kala Patthar is, however, completely festooned with prayer flags, making it quite readily recognizable. It is that summit that was recorded as 5,643m.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
