<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="436">
	<TITLE>Mount Hotham</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<REFERENCE ID="1" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mount Hotham</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is a mountain in Victoria, Australia. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="2" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="nominative" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="pronoun" TYPE="pronoun">It</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is home to Mount Hotham Village, and Mount Hotham Ski Resort. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="3" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">The mountain</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is located approximately 357 kilometres north east of Melbourne, 746 kilometres from Sydney, and 997 kilometres from Adelaide by road. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="4" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="subj-det">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="genitive" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mount Hotham's</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> summit rises to an altitude of 1,861 metres above sea level, while Mount Hotham village stands tall at a height of 1,750 metres AHD.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<STRING>Currently, Mt. Hotham holds the record for the highest annual snowfall of any Victorian resort over the past decade. Most of the skiing is based on one side of a large valley, and the area connects to the Bogong High Plains.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="3">
		<STRING>Mt. Hotham features 3.2 square kilometres of ski area, including 35 kilometres of tree-lined cross-country trails and a network of 13 lifts. The longest run at Mount Hotham is 2.5 kilometres long. Mount Hotham features an abundance of runs for skiers and boarders of all standards from beginners (20%) to intermediates (40%) and advanced (40%). The resort is home to one of Australia's most difficult runs, the steep Mary's Slide. A list of every ski tow to ever operate at Hotham can be found at wikiski.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
