<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="463">
	<TITLE>Mount Korab</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<REFERENCE ID="1" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mount Korab</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> (Macedonian: Голем Кораб, Golem Korab; Albanian: Maja e Korabit/Mali i Korabit) is the highest mountain of the Republic of Macedonia and Albania, </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="2" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="subj-det">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="genitive" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="pronoun" TYPE="pronoun">its</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> peak forms a frontier between the two countries. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="3" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">The Korab mountain</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is adjacent to the Aar Mountain.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<REFERENCE ID="4" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">The mountain</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> has a number of peaks that are higher than 2500 metres. The most important ones are:* Great Korab (in Macedonian: Голем Кораб (Golem Korab) or Кобилино Поле (Kobilino Pole), Albanian: Maja e Korabit/Mali i Korabit); height from the sea level 2753 m (older data) or 2764 m (newer data confirmed by GPS).* Kepi Bar (2,595 m)* Mala Korapska Vrata (2425 m; older data)* Kabash (2,395 m)* Ciganski Premin (2,295 m)* Plocha (2,235 m)* Visoka Karpa (2,090 m). These peaks are occasionally ruptured by radial tectonics in the shape of blocks that end in the valley of the Radika river on the Macedonian side. These blocks occasionally have steep slopes that reach up to 500 m. Particularly remarkable is also the alpine area of Kabash with several sheer and hardly approachable peaks. In its highest part, above 2,000 m, the climate is alpine and includes some alpine flora elements.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="3">
		<STRING>The state border intersects the higher peak, Great Korab.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="4">
		<STRING>During the Macedonian conflict in 2001, a front was on </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="5" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">the Korab</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING>, and there is still a mined zone around </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="6" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">the mountain</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING>. Ascending </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="7" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">the mountain</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is possible from the Macedonian side after complicated bureaucratic procedures, accompanied by a military escort.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="5">
		<STRING>There are no formal restrictions on climbing </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="8" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">the mountain</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> from the Albanian side. The area is now safer and more stable than it has been in recent times, and local inhabitants are generally welcoming and helpful. It is possible to drive as far as the local village of Radomirё, but the local infrastructure is generally not good. A four wheel drive vehicle with high clearance may be required. There are no accurate and up to date maps, local signposting is poor, and hikers may have to overcome the additional problem of aggressive dogs.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="6">
		<STRING>The best chance to climb </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="9" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Golem Korab</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is to join the International climb that is taking part every year in beginning of September. This climb is organized by the mountain club PSD &quot;Korab&quot; - Skopje.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
