<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="567">
	<TITLE>Mount Thor</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<REFERENCE ID="1" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mount Thor</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING>, officially gazetted as Thor Peak, is a mountain in Auyuittuq National Park, on Baffin Island, Nunavut, Canada. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="2" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">The mountain</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is located 46 km (29 mi) northeast of Pangnirtung and </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="3" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="" EMPHATIC="" HEAD="" TYPE="empty">_</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> features the Earth's greatest purely vertical drop at 1,250 metres (4,100 feet), with an average angle of 105 degrees. The location is popular with climbers due to this feature, despite its remoteness. Camping is allowed, with the only official site being at the entrance to the Akshayuk Valley near Overlord Peak.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<REFERENCE ID="4" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mount Thor</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is part of the Baffin Mountains which in turn form part of the Arctic Cordillera mountain range. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="5" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">The mountain</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is made of granite and </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="6" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="" EMPHATIC="" HEAD="" TYPE="empty">_</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is the most famous of Canada's mountains named &quot;Thor&quot;.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="3">
		<REFERENCE ID="7" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mount Thor</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> was first climbed in 1953 by an Arctic Institute of North America team. The team members were Hans Weber, J Rothlisberger and F. Schwarzenbach. The same men who climbed the North Tower of Mount Asgard for the first time.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="4">
		<STRING>The world record for longest rappel was set on </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="8" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mount Thor</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING>, July 23, 2006, by an American team consisting of: Chuck Constable, Dirk Siron, Ben Holley, Kenneth Waite, Gordon Rosser, Donny Opperman, Deldon Barfuss, and Tim Hudson. A 26 year old Canadian Park Ranger, Phillip Robinson, also rappelled, but had a problem with his equipment, dropped to the base of the mountain and was killed. There had been a previous attempt in 2004, but they returned without rappelling due to dangerous weather conditions.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="5">
		<REFERENCE ID="9" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mount Thor</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is used in the Led Zeppelin concert film The Song Remains the Same in the &quot;No Quarter&quot; fantasy sequence; the song mentioning the god Thor.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
