<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="455">
	<TITLE>Mount Kembla</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<STRING>Mount Kembla () is a mountain in New South Wales, Australia, as well a suburb of Wollongong, which gets its name from </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="1" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">the mountain</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING>. Kembla is an Aboriginal word meaning &quot;plenty of game&quot;. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="2" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="nominative" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="pronoun" TYPE="pronoun">It</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is a former coal mining town and the home of the miners killed in the Mount Kembla Mining Disaster. The township contains a local primary school, general store/post office, church and graveyard, several hundred houses and the Mount Kembla Hotel, which was built in the 1887. The only two ways into the village are from Wollongong, up the residential/bushland Cordeaux Road, its name coming from early settlers, and over from Mount Keira down Harry Graham Drive. The small village of Kembla Heights is part of the suburb but to the northwest, reached by Harry Graham Drive. The Mount Kembla Colliery was opened in 1883. BHP Billiton is a mining/steel export company which owns substantial property on and around </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="3" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mount Kembla</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING>. It is currently mining at the Dendrobium site, half a kilometre west of the village. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="4" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mount Kembla</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is joined to the west by the Illawarra escarpment and in particular a mass with two lower summits, Kembla West (512 m) and Mount Burelli (531 m). </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="5" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">The mountain</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> forms a prominent peak pointing roughly eastwards.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
