<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="528">
	<TITLE>Mount San Antonio</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<REFERENCE ID="1" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mount San Antonio</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING>, better known to most in Los Angeles as Old Baldy or Mount Baldy, is the highest peak in the San Gabriel Mountains of Southern California, USA and the highest point in Los Angeles County. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="2" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mount San Antonio</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> has two summits. The eastern summit is higher at an elevation of 10,064 feet while the west is at 9,988 feet. In winter, </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="3" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="subj-det">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="genitive" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mount Baldy's</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> snow-capped peaks are usually visible on clear days and dominate the view of the Los Angeles skyline.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<REFERENCE ID="4" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">The peak</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING>, </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="5" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="nominative" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="rel-pron" TYPE="pronoun">which</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> marks a boundary between San Bernardino County and Los Angeles County is called Baldy because of the absence of trees around the summit. The Tongva tribe call </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="6" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">the mountain</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> Yoát or Joat, which means snow.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="3">
		<REFERENCE ID="7" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">The peak</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> may host more hikers than any other mountaintop in the western United States (of those inaccessible by car), or so guesses San Gabriel Mountains historian John W. Robinson.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="4">
		<REFERENCE ID="8" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="nominative" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="pronoun" TYPE="pronoun">It</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is considered to be a cosmic spiritual &quot;recharging&quot; site by the Aetherius Society. The Mount Baldy Zen teaching centre was founded on </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="9" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mount San Antonio</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> in 1972 .</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="5">
		<REFERENCE ID="10" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mount Baldy</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING>, along with the nearby peak known as Thunder Mountain, is currently home to the family owned and operated ski resort Mount Baldy Ski Lifts, the closest resort to Los Angeles. Nearby lies Mt. Baldy Village, a small seasonal community. The village has its own fire department, church, visitor's center, and one-school school district; Mt. Baldy School (the abbreviation is the standard usage) has about 88 students.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="6">
		<STRING>Between 1922 and 1927, American physicist Albert Michelson performed a number of experiments involving bouncing a beam of light onto a reflector at Lookout Mountain, a prominent bump on the south ridge of </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="11" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">the mountain</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> 3km SW of the peak, from the observatory at Mount Wilson some 22 miles distant. The exact distance was very accurately surveyed and using the measurements the speed of light was calculated to be 299,796±4 km/s.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="7">
		<STRING>Nearby is San Antonio Creek, the location of San Antonio Falls. The creek cascades through a gorge about three times, the final of which is about a 75 foot drop.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
