<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="499">
	<TITLE>Mount Niblock</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<REFERENCE ID="1" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mount Niblock</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is a mountain in Banff National Park near Lake Louise, Alberta, Canada.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<REFERENCE ID="2" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">The mountain</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> was named in 1904 after John Niblock, a superintendent with the Canadian Pacific Railway. Niblock was an early promoter of tourism in the Rockies and influenced the naming of some of the CPR stops in Western Canada.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="3">
		<REFERENCE ID="3" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mt. Niblock</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is a popular scramble in the Lake Louise area and </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="4" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="" EMPHATIC="" HEAD="" TYPE="empty">_</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is sometimes combined in the same day with Mount Whyte (2,983m), although the latter is a more difficult scramble. The best time for climbing </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="5" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mt. Niblock</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is July through September when the normal route is usually free of snow. Attempting it in the spring or early summer may include significant avalanche hazard.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="4">
		<STRING>To access </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="6" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mt. Niblock</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING>, follow the trail as it begins near Chateau Lake Louise, passes Mirror Lake (Alberta) and then Lake Agnes. Follow the right hand shore line trail to the far end of the lake until it begins it left turn towards the Big Beehive. Here an obvious path can be found leading to the lower scree slopes and short cliffs. A more detailed route description can be found in Scrambles in the Canadian Rockies.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
