<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="521">
	<TITLE>Mount Rogers</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<REFERENCE ID="1" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mount Rogers</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is the highest point in the state of Virginia, USA, with a summit elevation of 5,729 feet (1,746 metres) above mean sea level. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="2" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="nominative" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="pronoun" TYPE="pronoun">It</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is in Grayson County, about 6.45 miles WSW of Troutdale, Virginia, within the Mount Rogers National Recreation Area.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<STRING>The summit is most easily accessed from Grayson Highlands State Park using a well marked trail system. It is covered by trees and marked with a National Geodetic Survey triangulation station disk. The Appalachian Trail passes right beneath the summit and thus the area is especially popular with hikers.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="3">
		<STRING>The Mount Rogers area contains a unique record of the geohistory of Virginia. There is evidence from the rocks that volcanoes were part of the landscape, but not for about 200 million years. Roughly 750 million years ago, rift-related (divergent) volcanoes erupted along the axis of what later became the Appalachians, and one remnant of that volcanic zone, with its volcanic rocks, still can be seen at </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="3" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mount Rogers</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING>. Massive rhyolite lava flows erupted at </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="4" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">the mountain</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> during the Precambrian rifting event. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="5" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mount Rogers</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is also the only place in Virginia that preserves evidence of ancient glaciation.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
