<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="402">
	<TITLE>Mount Edith Cavell</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<REFERENCE ID="1" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mount Edith Cavell</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is located in the Athabasca River and Astoria River valleys of Jasper National Park, Canada. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="2" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">The mountain</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> was named in 1916 for Edith Cavell, an English nurse executed by the Germans during World War I for having helped persons held captive to escape to refuge.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<STRING>A close up view of the north face of </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="3" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mt. Edith Cavell</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is visible after a short hike to Cavell Meadows. The trailhead is by the parking lot at the end of Mt. Edith Cavell road. The trail to the meadows is one way, rising 370 metres to 2,135 metres. The Canadian Rockies Trail Guide describes the trail in detail.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="3">
		<STRING>The hanging Angel Glacier is visible from Cavell Meadows, which spills over a 300 metre cliff on the north face.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="4">
		<STRING>Access to the Tonquin Valley trails can be found about 1km before then end of the Mt. Edith Cavell road. There is a parking area across from the Hostelling Internation Mt. Edith Cavell Hostel. A short walk down the gravel path leads to the north end of Cavell Lake. There is small bridge across the stream that empties the lake. From here you have a good view with the lake in the foreground and the Mt. Edith Cavell peaks in the background.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
