<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="466">
	<TITLE>Mount Langley</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<REFERENCE ID="1" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mount Langley</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is located on the crest of the Sierra Nevada Mountains, on the border of Inyo and Tulare counties, in eastern California in the southwestern United States. To the east is Owens Valley, and to the west is the Kern River Valley. At 14,026 feet (4,275 m), </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="2" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="nominative" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="pronoun" TYPE="pronoun">it</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is the ninth highest peak in the state, and the seventh highest in the Sierras. Mount Whitney, the highest peak in the contiguous United States, lies 5 miles (8 km) to the northwest. The Geological survey marker at the summit shows an elevation of 14,042 feet.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<STRING>Today, </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="3" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">the mountain</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is named after Samuel Pierpont Langley. In the early 1870s, </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="4" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="nominative" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="pronoun" TYPE="pronoun">it</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> was confused with Mount Whitney by early climbers, and called by this name. When the mistake was realized, </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="5" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">the peak</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> was alternately called Mount Corcoran, Cirque Peak, or Sheep Mountain; the former two names being later attached to other mountains. But </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="6" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="subj-det">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="genitive" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="pronoun" TYPE="pronoun">its</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> current name became established in local usage, and was made official by the USGS.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="3">
		<REFERENCE ID="7" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mount Langley</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is one of the easiest of California's fourteeners to climb. A hiking trail starts at nearby Horseshoe Meadow (elevation of around 10,000 feet), passes scenic Cottonwood Lakes, and climbs through New Army Pass. From there climbers make their way across a mountain meadow and up a long gradual slope of rock and gravel before making a Class 2 scramble to the summit. New Army pass is 7 miles from the trail head at Horseshoe meadow and is a more difficult approach to </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="8" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Langley</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> than Old Army Pass, which is recommended for hikers to </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="9" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Langley</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> when the trail is not impassable due to snow.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
