<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="1124">
	<TITLE>Nassau, Bahamas</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<REFERENCE ID="1" SEMCAT="city" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Nassau</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is the capital city and commercial centre of the Commonwealth of the Bahamas. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="2" SEMCAT="city" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">The city</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> has a population of 210,832 (2000 census), nearly 70 percent of the entire population of the Bahamas (303,611). Lynden Pindling International Airport, the major airport for the Bahamas, is located about 16 kilometres or 10 miles west of downtown Nassau, and has daily flights to major cities in the USA, Canada, the UK, and the Caribbean.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<STRING>Located on New Providence island, </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="3" SEMCAT="city" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Nassau</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> has an attractive harbour, a colourful blend of old world and colonial architecture and a busy port. The tropical climate and natural beauty of the Bahamas has made </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="4" SEMCAT="city" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Nassau</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> a popular tourist destination, with a reputation for relaxing days and an exciting nightlife.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="3">
		<STRING>Summertime temperatures rarely exceed 33 degrees Celsius (92 degrees Fahrenheit) and the winter months are very comfortable with daytime temperatures between 20 and 26 째C (68 and 80 째F), rarely falling below 10 째C or 50 째F.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="4">
		<REFERENCE ID="5" SEMCAT="city" SYNCAT="subj-det">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="genitive" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">The city's</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> proximity to the United States (180 miles or either 330 km or 290 km east-southeast of Miami, Florida) has also contributed to </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="6" SEMCAT="city" SYNCAT="subj-det">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="genitive" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="pronoun" TYPE="pronoun">its</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> popularity as a vacation spot, especially after the banning of American travel to Cuba. Attracting the majority of tourists and employing over 6,000 Bahamians--the largest outside of government--is the world famous Atlantis resort on nearby Paradise Island.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="5">
		<REFERENCE ID="7" SEMCAT="city" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">The city</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> also boasts of Junkanoo, an energetic, colourful street parade of brightly costumed people dancing to the rhythmic accompaniment of cowbells, drums and whistles. The celebration occurs on December 26th and January 1st, beginning in the early hours of the morning (1:00 a.m.) and ending at dawn.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
