<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="1733">
	<TITLE>Sari Nusseibeh</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<REFERENCE ID="1" SEMCAT="person" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Sari Nusseibeh</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> (born in 1949), is a Palestinian professor of philosophy and president of the Al-Quds University in Jerusalem (Al Quds is the Arabic name for Jerusalem). </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="2" SEMCAT="person" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="nominative" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="pronoun" TYPE="pronoun">He</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> was also, until December 2002, the representative of the Palestinian National Authority in Jerusalem. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="3" SEMCAT="person" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="nominative" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="pronoun" TYPE="pronoun">He</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> was born in Sheikh Jarrah, East Jerusalem to the politician Anwar Nusseibeh and Nuzha Al Ghussein, descended from Palestine's wealthy landed aristocracy and daughter of Palestinian political leader Yaqub al-Ghusayn. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="4" SEMCAT="person" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Sari</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> has a Ph.D. in Philosophy, from Harvard University (1978).</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<REFERENCE ID="5" SEMCAT="person" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Sari Nusseibeh</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> and Ami Ayalon are the co-founders of The People's Voice, an Israeli-Palestinian civil initiative that aims to advance the process of achieving peace between Israel and the Palestinians. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="6" SEMCAT="person" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Nusseibeh</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is head and founder of the Palestinian Consultancy Group, co-founder and member of several Palestinian institutions including the Jerusalem Friends of the Sick Society, the Federation of Employees in the Education Sector in the West Bank, the Arab Council for Public Affairs, the Committee Confronting the Iron Fist, and the Jerusalem Arab Council. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="7" SEMCAT="person" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="nominative" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="pronoun" TYPE="pronoun">He</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is also on the advisory board of The International Center for Ethics, Justice and Public Life at Brandeis University.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="3">
		<REFERENCE ID="8" SEMCAT="person" SYNCAT="subj-det">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="genitive" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Nusseibeh's</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> publications include numerous articles and, with Mark Heller, No Trumpets, No Drums: A Two-State Solution of the Israeli- Palestinian Conflict, New York: Hill &amp; Wand, 1991.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
