<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="718">
	<TITLE>Schreckhorn</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<REFERENCE ID="1" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">The Schreckhorn</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> (4,078 m) is a mountain in the Aarmassif in the Bernese Alps.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<STRING>The first ascent was on 16 August 1861 by Leslie Stephen, Ulrich Kaufmann, Christian Michel and Peter Michel. Their route of ascent, via the upper Schreck Couloir to the Schrecksattel and then by the south-east ridge, was the normal route for the following fifty years, but is now seldom used.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="3">
		<REFERENCE ID="2" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">The peak</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> had been attempted several times before this, most notably by the Swiss naturalist Joseph Hugi in 1828 (</STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="3" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="subj-det">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="genitive" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">the Schreckhorn's</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> Hugisattel is named after him) and the guided party of Pierre Jean Édouard Desor (a Swiss geologist) in 1842. 'The ambition of hoisting the first flag on the Schreckhorn, the one big Bernese summit which was untrodden, was far too obvious for us to resist', Desor later wrote, but they climbed a secondary summit of the Lauteraarhorn by mistake.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="4">
		<STRING>The first ascent by the south-west ridge (AD+) – the normal route by which </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="4" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">the Schreckhorn</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is climbed – was by an unguided British party comprising Edward Branby, John Wicks and Claude Wilson on 26 July 1902. The north-west ridge (the Andersongrat, AD) was first climbed by John Stafford Anderson and George Percival Baker, with guides Ulrich Almer and Aloys Pollinger on 7 August 1883.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="5">
		<STRING>The Strahlegg Hut, destroyed by an avalanche, has been replaced by the Schreckhorn Hut (2,520 m). </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="5" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">The Schreckhorn</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> may also be ascended from the Gleckstein Hut (2,317 m) and the Lauteraar Hut (2,392 m).</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
