<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="1369">
	<TITLE>Serbia</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<REFERENCE ID="1" SEMCAT="country" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Serbia</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING>, officially the Republic of Serbia (Serbian: [] or Republika Srbija, listen), is a landlocked country in Central and Southeastern Europe, covering the central part of the Balkan Peninsula and the southern part of the Pannonian Plain. The capital is Belgrade. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="2" SEMCAT="country" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Serbia</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> borders Hungary to the north; Romania and Bulgaria to the east; Albania and the Republic of Macedonia to the south; and Montenegro, Croatia and Bosnia and Herzegovina to the west.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<STRING>Invited by Byzantine emperor Heraclius Serbs settled the region by 630 A.D., fully converted to Christianity by 865 A.D., formed two distinct independent kingdoms by the 13th century- in Dioclea and Rascia , as well as two distinct shortlasting Empires- Serbian Empire of Stefan Dusan and Empire of Jovan Nenad . The Medieval Serbian Kingdom, later Empire, rose from Byzantine, Bulgarian and Hungarian patronage to become a threat to the very existence of Constantinople itself. Under a string of accomplished leaders, from Stefan Nemanja, through the Czar Stefan Dusan The Great, and culminating with the death of Prince Lazar at Kosovo in 1389, the medieval Serbs created a political entity which today still resonates strongly in the Serbian culture.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="3">
		<STRING>Placed under Ottoman occupation in the 15th century following the collapse of the Serbian Empire, the uprisings against Turkish occupation between 1804-1815 reestablished </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="3" SEMCAT="country" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Serbia</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> as a state </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="4" SEMCAT="country" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="nominative" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="rel-pron" TYPE="pronoun">which</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> obtained formal independence in 1878. Victorious in Balkan wars and World War I, for nearly a century </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="5" SEMCAT="country" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Serbia</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> was part of various South Slavic states, including the Kingdom of the Serbs, Croats and Slovenes from 1918 to 1941 (renamed to the Kingdom of Yugoslavia in 1929), the Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia from 1945 to 1992, the Federal Republic of Yugoslavia from 1992 to 2003, and the State Union of Serbia and Montenegro from 2003 to 2006. After Montenegro voted independence from the State Union, </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="6" SEMCAT="country" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Serbia</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> officially proclaimed </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="7" SEMCAT="country" SYNCAT="subj-det">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="genitive" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="pronoun" TYPE="pronoun">its</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> independence on June 5, 2006, as the successor state to the State Union of Serbia and Montenegro.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
