<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="838">
	<TITLE>Siula Grande</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<REFERENCE ID="1" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Siula Grande</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is a mountain in the Cordillera Huayhuash, in the Peruvian Andes. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="2" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="nominative" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="pronoun" TYPE="pronoun">It</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is 6344 m high and </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="3" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="" EMPHATIC="" HEAD="" TYPE="empty">_</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> has a subpeak Siula Chico 6260 m high.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<REFERENCE ID="4" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="nominative" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="pronoun" TYPE="pronoun">It</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> was made famous by the book Touching the Void by Joe Simpson, about an ascent and subsequent harrowing descent of </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="5" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">the mountain</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> by him and Simon Yates in 1985. The book was made into a film of the same title in 2003. Although they ascended the West face, and thereby became the first to reach the summit by that route, they chose the North Ridge (first descended in 1936 by a German team) for their descent, which was made almost impossible by horrible weather. All subsequent climbers have avoided the ridge and rappelled back down the face. As of 2002 the south face has been unconquered.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="3">
		<STRING>This is a partial list of first ascents by new routes made.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="4">
		<STRING>* 1936 July 28 North Ridge by Arnold Awerzger and Erwin Schneider from Germany.    * 1966 June 21 fourth ascent by Obster, Schulz and M. Sturm via the North ridge enroute to Siula Chico    * 1985 West Face by Joe Simpson and Simon Yates    * 1999 Peru West Face Touching The Void (new route) by Carlos Buhler. (Buhler's route followed the Yates/Simpson route for much of the ascent, and Buhler christened it &quot;Avoiding The Touch&quot;)    * 2001 July 17 Noches de &quot;Juerga&quot;, west face    * 2002 July 3 Northeast Face, Los Rapidos by two Slovenians - Marjan Kovac and Pavle Kozjek    * 2002 August Mammut Tracks, west face, by Rogier van Rijn and Eva Oomen</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
