<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="890">
	<TITLE>Torreys Peak</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<REFERENCE ID="1" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Torreys Peak</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is a mountain in the Front Range region of the Rocky Mountains in Colorado. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="2" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="nominative" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="pronoun" TYPE="pronoun">It</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is one of 54 fourteeners in Colorado. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="3" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="subj-det">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="genitive" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="pronoun" TYPE="pronoun">Its</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> nearest major city is Denver. The first man to ascend </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="4" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Torreys Peak</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING>, botanist Charles C. Parry, named </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="5" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">the peak</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> for his botanist colleague John Torrey. Torrey actually did not see </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="6" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">the peak</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> until 1872, 11 years later. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="7" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="nominative" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="pronoun" TYPE="pronoun">It</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is nearly always mentioned in conjunction with nearby Grays Peak. </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="8" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-subj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Torreys Peak</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> is located along the Continental Divide, as well as the division between Clear Creek County and Summit County.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<STRING>There are three main trails used to reach the summit. The first is actually a continuation of the main trail to the summit of Grays Peak, which starts in Stevens Gulch. See the Grays Peak article for more information on accessing that trail.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="3">
		<STRING>A popular and challenging variation of this trail follows class-3 Kelso Ridge. This route splits from the Grays Peak trail two miles from the trailhead, climbs to the 12,400 foot saddle between </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="9" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Torreys</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> and 13,164 foot Kelso Mountain, then follows the rugged ridge about a mile to the summit.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="4">
		<STRING>The third trail starts at Loveland Pass about 4.5 miles to the northwest. To reach Loveland Pass, follow I-70 west from Denver 55 miles to where US Route 6 breaks off and heads south. Follow the meandering Route 6 approximately seven miles to the trailhead at Loveland Pass, at an elevation of 11,990 feet.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="5">
		<STRING>The steepest part of the trail actually begins right away with a half mile climb of 1,000 feet. The trail follows the Continental Divide gently taking the climber down into three saddles and up two more peaks, including Grizzly Peak (13,427 feet). The final saddle rests at approximately 12,600. From this saddle, it is a mile-long ascent of 1,800 feet to the final summit.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="6">
		<STRING>Once at the summit, many opt to continue on to Grays Peak, 0.75 miles away. The trail from </STRING>
		<REFERENCE ID="10" SEMCAT="mountain" SYNCAT="np-obj">
			<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
				<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Torreys Peak</REFEX>
			</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
		</REFERENCE>
		<STRING> to Grays Peak dips down to a 13,707 foot saddle and then climbs back up to 14,270 feet.</STRING>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
