<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="75">
	<TITLE>Cerro de la Estrella</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<SENTENCE ID="1.1">
			<REFERENCE ID="1" PARAGRAPH-POSITION="1" PARAGRAPH-RECENCY="0" SEMCAT="mountain" SENTENCE-POSITION="1" SENTENCE-RECENCY="0" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Cerro de la Estrella</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> (from Spanish, meaning Hill of the Star) is a small mountain associated with several pre-Columbian Mesoamerican archaeological sites, located in southeastern Central Mexico's Valley of Mexico.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="1.2">
			<STRING>The site is contained within the urban sprawl of present-day Mexico City, in the Iztapalapa delegación (borough) of the Mexican Federal District. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<SENTENCE ID="2.1">
			<STRING>One of the sites is a 1,500 year old pyramid structure associated with the Classic-era Teotihuacano culture, which is located underneath a Roman Catholic religious site from the Colonial period.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.2">
			<STRING>Originally rediscovered and described in 1972, the structure was rediscovered on April 5, 2006 with much accompanying fanfare.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.3">
			<STRING>The 60-foot tall pyramid was originally carved from the hillside in 500 B.C., some 2,000 years before the Spanish conquest of Mexico.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.4">
			<STRING>It was abandoned in about 800 A.D..</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.5">
			<STRING>It measures 500 feet on each side.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.6">
			<STRING>Ceramic fragments and ceremonial structures convinced archaeologist Miriam Advincula to begin mapping the area in 2004. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="3">
		<SENTENCE ID="3.1">
			<STRING>Archaeologist Jesús Sánchez said, &quot;When they first saw us digging there, the local people just couldn't believe there was a pyramid.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="3.2">
			<STRING>It was only when the slopes and shapes of the pyramid, the floors with altars were found, that they finally believed us.&quot;</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="3.3">
			<STRING>Noting the important Holy Week celebrations on the site, he said &quot;Both the pre-Hispanic structure and the Holy Week rituals are part of our cultural legacy, so we have to look for a way to protect both cultural values.&quot;</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="4">
		<SENTENCE ID="4.1">
			<STRING>Another important archaeological site on  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="2" PARAGRAPH-POSITION="6" PARAGRAPH-RECENCY="0" SEMCAT="mountain" SENTENCE-POSITION="6" SENTENCE-RECENCY="0" SYNCAT="np-obj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Cerro de la Estrella</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> is the Aztec New Fire temple.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="4.2">
			<REFERENCE ID="3" PARAGRAPH-POSITION="13" PARAGRAPH-RECENCY="7" SEMCAT="mountain" SENTENCE-POSITION="1" SENTENCE-RECENCY="0" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Cerro de la Estrella</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> was known as &quot;Huixachtepetl&quot; (&quot;hill of the huisache&quot;) in Aztec times.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="4.3">
			<STRING>In the Aztec calendrical renewal ceremony known as the &quot;New fire ceremony&quot; priests observed the heavens from this temple every 52 years to determine if the world would be destroyed by the gods or saved for another 52 years.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="4.4">
			<STRING>If the world was not to be destroyed, priests carried out a sacrifice and lit a new fire which was then carried to all towns in the Aztec Empire. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
