<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="241">
	<TITLE>Jbel Toubkal</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<SENTENCE ID="1.1">
			<REFERENCE ID="1" PARAGRAPH-POSITION="1" PARAGRAPH-RECENCY="0" SEMCAT="mountain" SENTENCE-POSITION="1" SENTENCE-RECENCY="0" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Jbel (Jebel) Toubkal</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> / Adrar n Toubkal is a mountain peak in southwestern Morocco.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="1.2">
			<STRING>At 4,167 metres,  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="2" PARAGRAPH-POSITION="16" PARAGRAPH-RECENCY="15" SEMCAT="mountain" SENTENCE-POSITION="4" SENTENCE-RECENCY="0" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="nominative" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="pronoun" TYPE="pronoun">it</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> is the highest peak in the Atlas Mountains and in North Africa.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="1.3">
			<REFERENCE ID="3" PARAGRAPH-POSITION="29" PARAGRAPH-RECENCY="13" SEMCAT="mountain" SENTENCE-POSITION="1" SENTENCE-RECENCY="0" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="nominative" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="pronoun" TYPE="pronoun">It</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> is located 63 km south of the city of Marrakech, in the Toubkal National Park.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="1.4">
			<STRING>The first ascent by Europeans was on 12 June 1923 by the Marquis de Segonzac, Vincent Berger and Hubert Dolbeau, but  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="4" PARAGRAPH-POSITION="66" PARAGRAPH-RECENCY="37" SEMCAT="mountain" SENTENCE-POSITION="22" SENTENCE-RECENCY="0" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">the mountain</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> may have been climbed before that date. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<SENTENCE ID="2.1">
			<STRING>Trekkers usually approach  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="5" PARAGRAPH-POSITION="4" PARAGRAPH-RECENCY="0" SEMCAT="mountain" SENTENCE-POSITION="4" SENTENCE-RECENCY="0" SYNCAT="np-obj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">the mountain</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> from the road-end village of Imlil.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.2">
			<STRING>Qualified local guides can be hired, as well as mules and porters, to carry equipment and food supplies higher into the mountains.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.3">
			<STRING>For experienced mountaineers guides are not required for the normal route, as it is an easy hike and orientation is not a problem.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.4">
			<STRING>Usage of the mules is questionable, as they are often being overloaded and mistreated, and there is no need to carry food or tents if you stay in the refuge. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="3">
		<SENTENCE ID="3.1">
			<STRING>The normal route starts with easy walk to the village of Aroumd.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="3.2">
			<STRING>Past Aroumd a floodplain is crossed and route follows the left slope of the valley southwards.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="3.3">
			<STRING>Valley bends to the east to the tiny settlement of Sidi Chamharouch, which has grown around a Muslim shrine.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="3.4">
			<STRING>At Sidi Chamharouch path leads over the stream and steeply uphill to the right side of the Isougouane valley which leads to two stone-built refuges (old Neltner Refuge and new Refuge du Toubkal) that are often used as base camp at 3,207m.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="3.5">
			<STRING>It is possible to buy good meals in the Refuge du Toubkal.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="3.6">
			<STRING>Tent can be pitched near the refuges for a small charge. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="4">
		<SENTENCE ID="4.1">
			<STRING>From that point a path crosses the stream, climbs a steep scree slope to the east and enters a valley (corrie), then climbs another steep slope to reach a col (Tizi'n'Toubkal at 3,940m).</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="4.2">
			<STRING>At the col the route turns left (northwards) to the summit ridge of  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="6" PARAGRAPH-POSITION="47" PARAGRAPH-RECENCY="0" SEMCAT="mountain" SENTENCE-POSITION="14" SENTENCE-RECENCY="0" SYNCAT="np-obj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Jbel Toubkal</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING>.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="4.3">
			<STRING>The 4,167m summit is crowned with a curious pyramidal metal frame and views take in most of the Atlas and Anti-Atlas Mountains. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="5">
		<SENTENCE ID="5.1">
			<STRING>The ascent during the summer (from May) is non-technical and easy, only complicated by steep and slippery scree slopes and altitude sickness.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="5.2">
			<STRING>Sturdy boots and proper (windproof) clothing is required, trekking poles are helpful on the scree.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="5.3">
			<STRING>An ice-axe may be needed on the remaining snowfields in the early summer. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="6">
		<SENTENCE ID="6.1">
			<STRING>It is possible to climb  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="7" PARAGRAPH-POSITION="6" PARAGRAPH-RECENCY="0" SEMCAT="mountain" SENTENCE-POSITION="6" SENTENCE-RECENCY="0" SYNCAT="np-obj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="description">the mountain</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> in two days - first day up to the refuge (around seven hours without mules), second day to the summit (around five hours) and back to Imlil (up to five hours). </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="7">
		<SENTENCE ID="7.1">
			<STRING>In summer the mountains can be very dry, but are sometimes subjected to storms.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="7.2">
			<STRING>Although the temperature should keep above zero during the day, freezing conditions are possible over 3,500m.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="7.3">
			<STRING>In winter the mountains are covered in snow and ice, and can be prone to avalanches.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="7.4">
			<STRING>Skiing is possible as the snow can lie to considerable depth and cover many rocky slopes.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="7.5">
			<STRING>Information about state of the route can be obtained at Marrakech tourist offices or at Imlil. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
