<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEXT ID="336">
	<TITLE>Mount Ainos</TITLE>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="1">
		<SENTENCE ID="1.1">
			<REFERENCE ID="1" PARAGRAPH-POSITION="1" PARAGRAPH-RECENCY="0" SEMCAT="mountain" SENTENCE-POSITION="1" SENTENCE-RECENCY="0" SYNCAT="np-subj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mount Aenos</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> or Ainos (Όρος Αίνος Ancient and Modern Greek) is the tallest mountain in Cephallonia, Greece.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="1.2">
			<STRING>The elevation at the top of the point stands at 1628 m (around 5,350 ft.).</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="1.3">
			<STRING>Its location is 38.116/38°07'00&quot; N, 20.666/20°40'00&quot; E. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="2">
		<SENTENCE ID="2.1">
			<STRING>Most of the mountain range is designated as a park area.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.2">
			<STRING>Pine forests are found between the elevations of 700 to 1200 m. At the elevation from sea level up to about 300 m, there are beaches, farmland, communities ranging from Argostoli to Poros are placed.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.3">
			<STRING>A main road connects Argostoli and Poros (40 km long) is commuted.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.4">
			<STRING>elevation of 300 to 500 m, olive and laurel trees are founded.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.5">
			<STRING>Above 1200 m, mountain slopes is mainly barren, rocky and harsh.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="2.6">
			<STRING>The mountain range covers almost 3/4 of the island from Poros to Assos. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="3">
		<SENTENCE ID="3.1">
			<STRING>A view of the Peloponnese (from Patras to Pyrgos, Psathopyrgos NE of Patras down to the Krestena area and tiny bits of Erymanthus valleys during clear and hazy-less days) and Aetolia along with the islands of Zante, Lefkada, and Ithaca is spectacularly seen.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="3.2">
			<STRING>Nightlights of almost all of Cephallonia's villages and Argostoli, Kyllini coast, Chlemoutsi, most of Zante, most of Lefkada, entire Ithaca and the islands appear in total darkness, after dusk and before dawn.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="3.3">
			<STRING>Some lights of Western Achaea, the Western Peloponnese and Aetoloacarnania (Western Aetolia and southern Acarnania), and from huge boats appears during clear nights. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="4">
		<SENTENCE ID="4.1">
			<STRING>Pure blue Mediterranean waters of the Ionian Sea, with parts of the inner Mediterranean Sea is shown during clear blue days (not most of the time).</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="4.2">
			<STRING>Ferry boats, roads, and planes can bee seen in the morning in the west and a view of boats using the waters of the bay of Patras are seen from mid to late afternoon.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="4.3">
			<STRING>The history of panorama features no lights before the 1950s.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="4.4">
			<STRING>The first night scenery of lights in  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="2" PARAGRAPH-POSITION="78" PARAGRAPH-RECENCY="0" SEMCAT="mountain" SENTENCE-POSITION="8" SENTENCE-RECENCY="0" SYNCAT="np-obj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mount Ainos</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> and the range started with Argostoli, Lixouri, Patras, and sometimes Pyrgos and later Zante.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="4.5">
			<STRING>The 1980s and the 1990s made the night sky look brighter with lights coming from smaller villages and towns, making most of the scenery of the land look brighter. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
	<PARAGRAPH ID="5">
		<SENTENCE ID="5.1">
			<STRING>No ski resorts are found on this mountain range, but there are beautiful caves to be seen in the north.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="5.2">
			<STRING>A highway passes over the mountain range connecting traffic from southwestern to the eastern part of the island is one of the only roads going into the mountain range.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="5.3">
			<STRING>Once designated as GR Highway/Interstate 50, passes in a valley with an elevation of 800m.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="5.4">
			<STRING>There are around 3,000 to 4,000 people living on the mountain range of  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="3" PARAGRAPH-POSITION="78" PARAGRAPH-RECENCY="0" SEMCAT="mountain" SENTENCE-POSITION="14" SENTENCE-RECENCY="0" SYNCAT="np-obj">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="plain" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Ainos</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING>.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="5.5">
			<STRING>Television signals began to pop up on  </STRING>
			<REFERENCE ID="4" PARAGRAPH-POSITION="86" PARAGRAPH-RECENCY="8" SEMCAT="mountain" SENTENCE-POSITION="8" SENTENCE-RECENCY="0" SYNCAT="subj-det">
				<ORIGINAL-REFEX>
					<REFEX CASE="genitive" EMPHATIC="no" HEAD="nominal" TYPE="name">Mount Ainos'</REFEX>
				</ORIGINAL-REFEX>
			</REFERENCE>
			<STRING> mountaintop.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="5.6">
			<STRING>It began with a TV transmitter in the 1970s.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="5.7">
			<STRING>Then a few more were added in the early 1990s to make Cephallonia's communications a little easier.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="5.8">
			<STRING>It is located not far from the mountaintop.</STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
		<SENTENCE ID="5.9">
			<STRING>There are also radio transmitters scattered all over the island. </STRING>
		</SENTENCE>
	</PARAGRAPH>
</TEXT>
